A Finding Aid to the David Bourdon papers, 1941-1998, in the Archives of American Art AAA.bourdavi
Archives of American Art
David Bourdon papers
1941-1998
AAA.bourdavi
Archives of American Art
37 Linear feet
The papers of New York art critic and writer David Bourdon measure 37 linear feet and date from 1941–1998. The papers include scattered biographical materials, manuscript and published writings, extensive art and artists' research files, and printed materials.
Bourdon, David
Biographical/Historical note
David Bourdon (1934-1998) was an art critic, editor, and author who worked primarily in New York City.
David Bourdon was born in 1934 in California but moved to New York City to attend Columbia University and continued to live there for most of his life. He wrote for numerous art publications and was known for his sharp insight and wit. From 1964 to 1966 and 1974 to 1977 he served as art critic for the Village Voice, was assistant editor of Life magazine from 1966 to 1971, associate editor of the Smithsonian Magazine from 1972 to 1974, and art critic for Vogue magazine from 1978 to 1983 when he became senior features editor. Bourdon was also a senior editor for GEO magazine in the early 1980s and New York correspondent for du magazine for about three years in the 1970s. He was a frequent contributor to Art in America, and, in the summer of 1977 produced a show-by-show review of the entire New York art season. Bourdon also served as president of the U.S. section of the International Association of Art Critics.
Bourdon was friends with many artists, including Andy Warhol, whom he met in the 1950s while Warhol was working as a commercial artist. Bourdon wrote a book on Warhol (1989) and was involved in the some of Warhol's Factory projects, including the 1963 series of Elvis Presley silk screens. Bourdon wrote about the Manhattan art world of the early 1960s and was one of the early writers on the Minimalist moement. He also wrote about the Earth Art movement in the 1960s-1970s and was friends with Robert Smithson and Michael Heizer. He wrote Designing the Earth: the Human Impulse to Shape Nature which was published in 1995. He also wrote books on Christo (1972) and Alexander Calder (1980).
David Bourdon died in 1998 at the age of 63.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The David Bourdon papers were donated to the Archives of American Art by Les Levine, executor of the David Bourdon estate.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of New York art critic and writer David Bourdon measure 37 linear feet and date from 1941–1998. The papers include scattered biographical materials, manuscript and published writings, extensive art and artists' research files, and printed materials.
Biographical materials consist of school writings; 2 folders of correspondence, including correspondence with Ray Johnson; Bourdon's mother’s family reminiscences, and other personal scattered materials. Writings include essays, stories, articles, and manuscript material for the books Calder: Mobilist, Ringmaster, Innovator (1980) and Designing the Earth: the Human Impulse to Shape Nature (1995). The bulk of Bourdon papers consist of his compiled research files on art, artists, sculpture, architecture and design, earth art, and for his book Designing the Earth. Individual research files may include printed materials, correspondence, writings, interview transcripts, notes, photographs, and press releases. Printed material covers many of the same subjects as those found in the research files as well Bourdon’s published writings.
Related Archival Materials note
Additional David Bourdon papers are located at the Museum of Modern Art Archives in New York.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 4 series. The found order has been maintained and is assumed to be that of David Bourdon.
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1949-1997 (0.6 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 2: Writings, 1941-1997 (1.2 linear feet; Boxes 1-2)
Series 3: Research files, 1945-1998 (25.8 linear feet; Boxes 2-28)
Series 4: Printed Material, 1962-1997 (linear feet; Boxes 28-39)
Andre, Carl, 1935-; Calder, Alexander, 1898-1976; Christo, 1935-; Johnson, Ray, 1927-; Warhol, Andy, 1928-; Art critics -- New York (State) -- New York; Art, Modern; Authors -- New York (State) -- New York; Pop art; Video recordings
- Biographical Materials, 1949-1997; 1; 0.6 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Scattered biographical materials include school notebooks, files on topics of interest, family events, and family history. There is one folder of miscellaneous correspondence and one folder of two items from Ray Johnson (additional Johnson correspondence can be found in Series 3, subseries 4.)
  Arrangement note
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Animals & Animal Welfare, 1985-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Apartment Decorating & Design, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Columbia University - Papers G.S. Fine Arts 44, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - General, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Ray Johnson, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Erasable Structures" - Visual Arts Gallery 1971 - Guest Directed by David Bourdon (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Garden Committee - 315 W. 23rd Street Owner's Corp., 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "I Have Seen it All" by Marilyn Bourdon nee Edith Casale, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - New Windsor Auction Gallery, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - North Hollywood High School - 25 Year Reunion Mini-Yearbook, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Notebook - Medieval - American Furniture, circa 1952-1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Notebooks - French etc., 1986, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13-15)
  - Photographs, circa 1960-1997 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - School Notebook, Writings, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Sharon" by David Bourdon, Jr., undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Studio of Modern Piano, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Telephone Numbers, circa 1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - University Papers, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Vacation, etc. Materials, 1985, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Writers Bloc - Flyer, circa 1961-1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Writings, 1941-1997; 2; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Arranged chronologically, except book materials which are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  Writings include essays, stories, articles, and research materials and manuscript drafts of Bourdon's books Calder and Designing the Earth (early drafts are titled “Earthbound”.) There are also drafts of his “Collected Writings,” some contracts, and a file marked current projects. Some files also include correspondence, press releases, brochures, clippings, and notes. Additonal writings are found among the research files, and published versions of Bourdon's writings are filed with Printed Materials.
  - Book - Calder, 1941-1991 (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - Book - Designing the Earth - Captions, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Book - Designing the Earth - Chapters 1-5, 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 27-31)
  - Book - Designing the Earth - Chapter 6, 1991-1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Book - Designing the Earth - Pictures, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Book - Designing the Earth - Pictures, Rejected, 1991-1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Book - Designing the Earth - Reviews, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Collected Writings" II - Pop Art, IV Happenings/Performance, V Abstraction, VI Figurative Art, VII Photography, circa 1967-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Collected Writings", circa 1967-1997 (Box 2, Folder 6-11)
  - Contracts, 1969-1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Current Projects, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Finished Stories & Articles, 1955-1991 (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
- Research files, 1945-1998; 3; 25.8 Linear feet Boxes 2-28, 39
  Bourdon assembled extensive research/subject files on a wide variety of art topics and artists, such as American art, art prices and collecting, forgeries, photography, sculpture, Gregory Battcock, Nam June Paik, Ray Johnson, and Pop art, among many other topics. There are extensive files on Andy Warhol and earth art in support of his books. Contents of folders vary, but typically include printed materials, contract agreements, correspondence, draft writings, interview transcripts, memos to editors, newsletters, notes, photographs, and press releases.
  Series 3 is arranged in 9 subseries.
  Location, 1945-1996
  Period, 1949-1997
  Style, 1953-1997
  Artist, 1945-1997
  Architecture & Design, 1955-1993
  Sculpture, 1959-1996
  Various Subjects, 1949-1997
  Andy Warhol, 1960-1998
  Designing the Earth: the Human Impulse to Shape Nature, 1955-1997
  - Location, 1945-1996; 3.1; 4.6 Linear feet Boxes 2-7
    Arranged alphabetically by location
    Locations include the United States, Asia, England, France, Germany, international, Italy, Russia etc.
    - U.S. 19th C-1908, 1958-1993 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    - U.S. 19th C-1908, 1958-1993 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    - U.S. 1908-1945 A-F, 1958-1996 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
    - U.S. 1908-1945 G-M, 1954-1993 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
    - U.S. 1908-1945 N-R, 1961-1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - U.S. 1908-1945 S-Z, 1957-1993 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
    - Asia, 1959-1994 (Box 3, Folder 11-13)
    - Austria, 1965-1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Belgian, 1976-1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cambodia, 1970-1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - England Pre-1960, 1956-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
    - England 1960-, 1964-1993 (Box 4, Folder 5-8)
    - French 19th C I, 1949-1991 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
    - French 19th C II, 1955-1985 (Box 4, Folder 11-13)
    - French 19th C III, 1954-1993 (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
    - French 19th C IV, 1983-1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - French 20th C Pre 1945 I of VI, 1964-1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - French 20th C Pre 1945 II of VI, 1948-1982 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
    - French 20th C Pre 1945 III of VI, 1964-1994 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - French 20th C Pre 1945 IV of VI, 1966-1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - French 20th C Pre 1945 Vof VI, 1949-1984 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - French 20th C Pre 1945 VI of VI, 1965-1996 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - French 20th C Post 1945 II, 1976-1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - French 20th C Post 1945 III, 1945-1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Germany Pre 1968, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Germany Pre 1968, 1957-1966 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Germany 1968-1980, 1968-1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Germany Post 1981, 1982-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - International I, 1953-1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - International II, 1969-1992 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - International IV, 1960-1991 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - International IV, 1960-1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - International 20th C I, 1958-1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - International 20th C II, 1957-1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Italy, 1958-1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Italy II, 1966-1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Italy, 1949-1989 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Italy, 1982-1991 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Latin American, 1981-1993 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Russia I, 1960-1989 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Russia II, 1958-1985 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Russia III, 1960-1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Russia - Kandinsky, 1956-1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Spanish, 1959-1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Swiss, 1962-1994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Period, 1949-1997; 3.2; 1.6 Linear feet Boxes 7-8
    Arranged alphabetically by period
    From ancient through the 18th century.
    - Antiques II, 1979-1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Antiques II, 1953-1993 (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
    - Antiques III, 1956-1977 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Archeology, 1957-1995 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Ancient, 1955-1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Ancient, 1959-1997 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Ancient, 1961-1990 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Medieval, 1947-1996 (Box 7, Folder 13-15)
    - Renaissance, 1955-1996 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Renaissance - 18th Century, 1958-1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Northern Renaissance, 1954-1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 17th & 18th Century, 1949-1996 (Box 8, Folder 5-8)
  - Style, 1953-1997; 3.3; 3.5 Linear feet Boxes 8-12
    Arranged alphabetically by style type
    From abstract, Art Deco, Dada, Pop to realism/figurative.
    - Abstract A-L 1961-1970, 1954-1970 (Box 8, Folder 9-11)
    - Abstract A-L 1971-1980 (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
    - Abstract A-L 1981-1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Abstract A-L 1991-, 1976-1997 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Abstract M-Z 1960-1989, 1957-1968 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
    - Abstract M-Z 1970-1980, 1970-1979 (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
    - Abstract M-Z 1981-1990 (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
    - Abstract M-Z 1991-, 1991-1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Abstract Expressionists -1959, 1953-1959 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Abstract Expressionists 1960-1969, 1961-1969 (Box 10, Folder 3-5)
    - Abstract Expressionists 1970-1979 (Box 10, Folder 6-8)
    - Abstract Expressionists 1980-1990, 1974-1997 (Box 10, Folder 9-10)
    - Abstract Expressionists 1991-2000, 1991-1996 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Art Deco / Nouveau, 1958-1995 (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
    - Art Deco / Nouveau, 1958-1995 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Dada, Surrealism, 1958-1993 (Box 11, Folder 2-5)
    - Pop, 1957-1995 (Box 11, Folder 6-9)
    - Pop Art Styles, 1965-1988 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Realism, Figurative A-L 1961-1980, 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Realism, Figurative M-Z 1950s-1970, 1959-1967 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Realism, Figurative A-L 1971-1980 (Box 11, Folder 13-14)
    - Realism, Figurative A-L 1971-1980 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Realism, Figurative A-L 1981-1990 (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
    - Realism, Figurative A-L 1991-, 1987-1997 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Realism, Figurative M-Z 1971-1980 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Realism, Figurative M-Z 1981-1990 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Realism, Figurative M-Z 1991-, 1994-1996 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Artist, 1945-1997; 3.4; 2.8 Linear feet Boxes 12-15
    Arranged alphabetically by Artist’s name
    Includes artists such as Diane Burko, Joseph Cornell, Jasper Johns, Ray Johnson (includes some correspondence, including mail art), Carlo Maria Mariani, Pablo Picasso, Jackson Pollock, and Robert Rauschenberg.
    - Andre, Carl, 1966-1992 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Andre, Carl - Krefelder Kunstmuseum, 1985-1996 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Asterlind, Mark, 1993-1996 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Beuys, Joseph, 1968-1993 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Burko, Diane, 1993-1995 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Cesar [Baldaccini], 1962-1997 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Cesar - Rel. Sculptures, 1956-1983 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Chamberlain, John et al, 1960-1990 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Chia, Sandro, 1981-1990 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Chia, Sandro, 1981-1990 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Christo - Reichstag, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 2-4)
    - Christo - Germany, 1989-1996 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Cornell, Joseph, 1966-1997 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Graves, Nancy, 1966-1996 (Box 13, Folder 7-9)
    - Hume, Gary, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Hunt, Bryan, 1977-1992 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Hunt, Bryan, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Johns, Jasper, 1959-1996 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Johnson, Ray - Articles on, Writings, 1963-1995 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Johnson, Ray, 1994-1995 (Box 13, Folder 15-16)
    - Johnson, Ray, 1945-1995 (Box 13, Folder 17-19)
    - Johnson, Ray, 1945-1995 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Lichtenstein, Roy, 1964-1982 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Liepke, Malcolm, 1990-1995 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Mariani, Carlo Maria, 1984-1997 (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
    - Nauman, Bruce, 1973-1996 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Oldenburg, Claes, 1960-1977 (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
    - Paik, Nam June, 1969-1997 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Paik, Nam June: Charlotte Moorman & Avant Garde Festival of New York, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Pearlstein, Philip, 1963-1997 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1955-1986 (Box 14, Folder 12-14)
    - Pollock, Jackson, 1956-1978 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Pollock, Jackson, 1956-1978 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Rauschenberg, Robert, 1960-1991 (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
    - Ruskin, John, 1962-1983 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - De Saint Phalle, Niki, circa 1985-1997 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Architecture & Design, 1955-1993; 3.5; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 15-16
    Arranged in original order with United States first and chronologically by time period, then International
    Includes the United States, divided by time periods from pre-1960 through 1980 forward, and International.
    - U.S. Pre 1960, 1955-1993 (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
    - U.S. 1960-1979 (Box 15, Folder 8-10)
    - U.S. 1980-, 1973-1991 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - International, 1955-1991 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - International, 1955-1991 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Sculpture, 1959-1996; 3.6; 2 Linear feet Boxes 16-18
    Arranged in original order with United States first, chronologically by time period, then International, chronologically by time period
    Includes United States abstract, 1950s through 1990s and figurative, 1960s through 1990s; international 1900 through 1990s.
    - U.S. Abstract through 1959, 1956-1996 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Abstract 1960-1970 (Box 16, Folder 4-6)
    - U.S. Abstract 1971-1980, 1959-1980 (Box 16, Folder 7-9)
    - U.S. Abstract 1981-1990, 1979-1990 (Box 16, Folder 10-12)
    - U.S. Abstract 1991-, 1991-1996 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Figurative 1950-1960, 1948-1960 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Figurative 1961-1970 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Figurative 1971-1980, 1970-1980 (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
    - U.S. Figurative 1981-1990, 1982-1991 (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
    - U.S. Figurative 1991-, 1991-1995 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - International 1900-1945, 1963-1994 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - International 1945-1959, 1955-1959 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - International 1960-1969, 1963-1972 (Box 17, Folder 11-12)
    - International 1970-1979 (Box 17, Folder 13-14)
    - International 1980-1989 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - International 1990-, 1988-1996 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Various Subjects, 1949-1997; 3.7; 6 Linear feet Boxes 18-24
    Arranged alphabetically by subject
    Includes collectors, crafts, critics, dancers, dealers and galleries, films, happenings, horses (for proposed book), museums, music, photography, tribal, and video art, among many others.
    - Art Shows, 1956-1993 (Box 18, Folder 2-3)
    - Animals, 1978-1996 (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
    - Battcock, Gregory, 1971-1975 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Books, 1953-1988 (Box 18, Folder 7-8)
    - Collectors, 1957-1987 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Collectors - Continued, 1949-1993 (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
    - Crafts, 1968-1991 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Crafts - Ceramics & Glass, 1963-1993 (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
    - Criticism, 1955-1987 (Box 19, Folder 4-6)
    - Critics, 1949-1991 (Box 19, Folder 7-9)
    - Dancers, 1975-1997 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Danse Macabre, 1987-1990 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Dealers, Galleries, 1962-1991 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Drawings & Prints 1961-1970, 1948-1970 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Drawings & Prints 1971-1980, 1969-1979 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Drawings & Prints 1971-1980, 1969-1979 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Drawings & Prints 1981-, 1981-1990 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Fakes & Forgeries, 1959-1986 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Films, 1961-1996 (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
    - Happenings 1960s, 1959-1969 (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
    - Happenings, Performance Art 1971-1980, 1961-1979 (Box 20, Folder 9-10)
    - Happenings, Performance Art 1981-, 1981-1995 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - "The Horse" - Miscellaneous, 1971-1997 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - "The Horse" - Articles to Look at, 1988-1995 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - "The Horse" - Natural Rights, 1983-1996 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - "The Horse" - Pictures - Y Rejects, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - "The Horse" - Pictures, Z Rejects, 1956-1980 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - "The Horse" Text, 1994-1996 (Box 21, Folder 2-3)
    - "Horse Power" - Pictures, 1988-1990 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - "Horse Power" Text, circa 1988-1990 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Museums - U.S. General, 1957-1992 (Box 21, Folder 6-8)
    - Museums - U.S., Los Angeles, 1957-1992 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Museums - U.S., New York City, 1954-1991 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Museums - U.S., New York City - Guggenheim, 1971-1992 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Museums - U.S., New York City - Metropolitan, 1957-1997 (Box 21, Folder 12-13)
    - Museums - U.S., New York City - MOMA, 1960-1988 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Museums - U.S., New York City - Whitney, 1961-1992 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Museums - U.S., Washington D.C. - Hirshhorn, 1966-1992 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Museums - International, 1949-1994 (Box 22, Folder 4-7)
    - Museums - Photographs, circa 1980-1997 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Ono, Yoko & Lennon, John, 1971-1996 (Box 22, Folder 9-10)
    - Orvieto, Italy - Postcards, circa 1952-1997 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Photographs, circa 1987-1997 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Photography 1920-, 1968-1994 (Box 22, Folder 13-16)
    - Photography 1920-, 1968-1994 (Box 23, Folder 1-4)
    - Photography - Conceptual, 1972-1995 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Prices, 1955-1993 (Box 23, Folder 6-7)
    - Restany, Pierre, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Revere Teapot, 1978-1995 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - 1960s Miscellaneous, 1963-1996 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Sociology, 1966-1995 (Box 23, Folder 11-13)
    - Themes, 1954-1995 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Tribal, 1958-1992 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Video, 1966-1995 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Andy Warhol, 1960-1998; 3.8; 2.8 Linear feet Boxes 24-26, 39
    Materials include correspondence, clippings, announcements, draft writings, interview materials, press releases, reviews, and notes, for 1989 book and various articles.
    - Andy Warhol Books, 1968-1979 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Andy Warhol Pals, 1965-1989 (Box 24, Folder 4-5)
    - Andy Warhol Museum, 1992, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Andy's Pals, 1972-1992 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Art of the 50s, 1960-1989 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Art 1962-1963, 1962-1986 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Art 1966-1967, 1965-1990 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Art 1968 & 1969, 1969-1984 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Art 1969-1972, 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Art 1964-1965, 1963-1988 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Art 1970s, 1970-1981 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Art of the 70s - 1973-1980 & Oxidation Paintings - 1978, 1974-1987 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Art of the 80s, 1980-1993 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Art Deco & Collections, 1972-1977 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Auction - Andy Warhol Collection, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Auctions - Estate, 1988-1990 (Box 24, Folder 19-20)
    - Bio 40s & 50s, 1966-1989 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Bio 1960-63, 1974, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Bio 60s 1966-1968, 1964-1968 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Bio 69-70, 1964-1988 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Bio 1971 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Bio 70s, 1970-1973 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Bio 70s 73-79, 1973-1979 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Bio 80s, 1978-1989 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - [Book] Abrams Contract, Style Sheets, Publicity, Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Book Publication and Reviews, 1989-1990 (Box 25, Folder 10-11)
    - Correspondence - Abrams re Warhol, etc re Other Books, 1969-1991 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Films 1963-65, 1964-1966 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Films 1966-69, 1966-1969 (Box 25, Folder 14-15)
    - Films 1970-72, 1970-1989 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Films 1973-, 1973-1988 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Films 80s, 1964-1986 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Films, 1989-1990 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Films - Chelsea Girls, 1966-1968 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Films - Lonesome Cowboy, 1968-1971 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Heinz Box, 1990-1991 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Interviews, Questions A-L, 1968-1987 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Interviews, Questions M-Z, 1964-1989 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Johnson, Jed - TWA Flight 800 Crash, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968-1997 (Box 26, Folder 1-6)
      Oversized material housed in Box 38, Folders 1 and 2
    - Miscellaneous Materials, 1968-1998 (Box 26, Folder 7)